https://smtd.umich.edu/privacy-policy/

Skip to content
SMTD COVID-19 INFORMATION
Information for:
Alumni
Search for:
youtube
MenuDegrees & ProgramsDegrees OfferedUndergraduateGraduateMinors & Certificates ClosePerformance Opportunities CloseEngagement & OutreachYouth ProgramsAdult ProgramsCommunity ProgramsEvents & NewsWays to Connect Close CloseAdmissionsApply Now CloseUndergraduate AdmissionsApplyArtistic & Academic PreparationRequirements for Pre-screening/Portfolios & Auditions/InterviewsUndergraduate Audition & Interview DatesDeadlinesCost, Scholarships & Financial AidTransfer AdmissionsHomeschooled & Online High School StudentsParents & Guardians CloseGraduate AdmissionsApplyArtistic & Academic PreparationRequirements for Pre-screening/Portfolios & Auditions/InterviewsGraduate Audition & Interview DatesDeadlinesCost, Scholarships & Financial Aid CloseInternational Admissions CloseNon-Degree Admission & Second Bachelor’s Degrees CloseFAQs CloseExplore & Visit CloseNew Students CloseContact Close ClosePerformances & EventsCalendar of EventsSMTD Ticket PoliciesMaps & DirectionsJoin Email ListJoin Usher Pool CloseDepartmentsChamber MusicCompositionConductingDanceEntrepreneurship & LeadershipJazz & Contemporary ImprovisationMusic EducationMusic TheoryMusical TheatreMusicologyOrganPerforming Arts TechnologyPianoStringsTheatre & DramaVoiceWinds & Percussion CloseResearch & CollectionsAboutLeadership CloseFaculty & Staff Profiles CloseFacilitiesBuildingsLarge Performance VenuesSmall Performance VenuesFacilities Available for Rental CloseDiversity, Equity & Inclusion CloseSMTD Climate CloseWellnessWellness FAQsWellness ProgramsWellness ResourcesWellness Team CloseNews CloseHistory CloseContact Us Close CloseGivingWays To GiveVictors for Michigan CampaignSMTD Friends Groups Close
Privacy Policy
Last update: May 25, 2018
This website uses Google Analytics to analyze how visitors use the site. The tool uses “cookies,” which are text files placed on your computer, to collect standard Internet log information and visitor behavior information in an anonymous form. The information generated by the cookie about your use of the website (including IP address) is transmitted to Google. This information is then used to evaluate visitors’ use of the website and to compile statistical reports on website activity. We will never (and will never allow any third party to) track or collect any Personally Identifiable Information of visitors to our site using analytics tools. Google will not associate your IP address with any other data held by Google. Neither we nor Google will link, or seek to link, an IP address with the identity of a computer user. More information about Google’s data collection.
We recognize and value the privacy of our website visitors, and strive to appropriately manage, secure, and keep private and confidential the personal data entrusted to us.
How We Collect Information
We collect personal information in the following circumstances:
Direct Collection: When you directly provide it to us, such as when you sign up for a newsletter or complete a form on one of our webpages.
Automated Processes: This includes information you provide us through technology, such as through a cookie placed on your computer when you visit our websites.
Our goal is to limit the information we collect to that which is needed to serve our visitors well and support the School’s mission.
How This Information Is Used
We collect and use information about user visits to monitor website performance, make improvements to site navigation and content, and better market to prospective students and other audiences.
We may also collect and use personal information provided by site visitors for educational programs, administrative purposes (e.g., related to employment), or university engagement (e.g., attending a sponsored event).
What Choices You Can Make About Your Information
To enhance your experience, we may place “cookies” on your computer or device. Cookies are files that store your preferences. When you access smtd.umich.edu, Google Analytics cookies may be placed on your device, depending on your web browser settings.
Purpose: Google Analytics cookies count visits and traffic sources in order to measure and improve the performance of our website. See details about Google Analytics’ usage of cookies on websites
and privacy policy
.
Opt-out: Find out more about managing cookies through your browser
.
How Information Is Secured
We recognize the importance of maintaining the security of the information we collect and maintain, and we endeavor to protect information from unauthorized access and damage. We strive to ensure reasonable security measures are in place, including physical, administrative, and technical safeguards to protect your personal information.
Privacy Notice Changes
This privacy notice may be updated from time to time. We will post the date our notice was last updated at the top of this privacy notice.
Who to Contact with Questions or Concerns
If you have any concerns or questions about how your personal data is used, please contact the webmaster at smtd.webmaster@umich.edu. We strive to promptly respond to your request, and will do our best to address your concern. However, if you believe we have not been able to deal with your concern appropriately, you have a right to complain to your local data protection authority. You also have the right to submit a complaint in the Member State of your residence or place of work of an alleged infringement of the GDPR.
Notice Specific to Persons within the European Union
If you are in the EU and you interact with the School of Music, Theatre & Dance in the context of this website, then our processing of your personal information may fall under Regulation 2016/679 (the General Data Protection Regulation, or the “GDPR”) and under the legal framework of Directive 2002/58/EC (“ePrivacy” Directive). In these circumstances and as applicable, the School may be the controller of the processing of your personal data. Please see also the Univeristy’s GDPR resources webpage for more information.
Legal Basis for Processing
When we process your personal information, we will endeavor to have a valid lawful ground for processing in place. We process your personal information relying on different lawful grounds for processing, depending on the context of the processing activity.
Your Rights
The School is committed to facilitating the exercise of the rights granted to you by EU data protection law (the right to access your data, to ask for erasure, correction, restriction, portability of your data or to object to the processing of your data) in a timely manner for personal information that properly falls under the GDPR.
In order to be able to reply to your request for exercise of your rights, and if we are not certain of your identity, we may need to ask you for further identification data to be used only for the purposes of replying to your request. If you have any inquiries or requests, please contact the webmaster at smtd.webmaster@umich.edu.
Retention Period
We strive to keep personal data in our records only as long as they are necessary for the purposes they were collected and processed. Retention periods vary and are established considering our legitimate purposes and all applicable legal requirements.
Transfers
When you interact with the School, your personal information is transferred to the United States. The United States is not currently among the countries outside the European Union that have obtained an adequate level of protection from the European Commission. To ensure the lawful transfers of personal data from the EU, the School relies on the derogations laid out in Article 49 GDPR. Be advised that we provide safeguards for the information transferred, as required by the GDPR itself and in accordance with this website privacy notice.
Contact Us
Directory
Maps & Directions
Facilities Rental
Privacy Policy
U-M Home
School of Music, Theatre & Dance
E.V. Moore Building, 1100 Baits Dr.
